(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-05T16:52:34.522353",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
踊りだそう話そう アナタこそ理想
Let's dance, let's talk, you are the ideal.
霧捨て ごめんの マジカルワールド
A magical world of slash and forgiveness.
IMP IMP 幻の呪文 IMP マジカルゴザル
IMP, IMP, a phantom spell, IMP, magical gozaru.
朝も目が覚めたら 時刻寸前
When I wake up in the morning, right before the time,
お気に入りの笑みも 吐いたなら
if I flash my favorite smile, and sigh,
駆け抜けるアルマジロ
an armadillo runs through.
もっと じゃきん じゃきん
More, clink, clink,
月夜 マジカルバンド だから絡みでもまあ
moonlit magical band, so even if we get entangled,
少女祭り ひねふぜあなたも
festival of maidens, flutter away, you too.
私服 ころやす 悪代官ブタチ
Plain clothes, killing easily, evil magistrate piggies,
ちょっとかよい だいぶかわいい
a bit naive, pretty cute.
拙者のワンダの サビになるでござる
it'll become the chorus of my wonder, gozaru!
マジカル バッド キリ！
Magical bad cut!
ござる ござる うちにでござる
Gozaru, gozaru, it's at my place,
マジカル なみねうちを お見舞い続けてござる
delivering magical waves continuously, gozaru.
ござる ござる この世界をまもる
Gozaru, gozaru, protecting this world,
完璧にカレンナ 姿をご覧あれ
behold my perfectly lovely figure.
魔法少女マジカルござる
Magical girl, magical gozaru.
振り振りひらひら 強風に舞う 袴の裾を
Swishing, fluttering, dancing in the strong gale, the hem of my hakama,
ちょっとつまんで 決めてこう 掲げよあなたも
gently pinching it, let's decide and raise it, you too.
ござる ランダの 麗しきお姫様
Gozaru, Randa's graceful princess,
だげど言えない その招待
but I can't say that invitation.
秘密こそ至上のテンプレートでござる
Secrets are the supreme template, gozaru.
ござる ござる 闇討ちでござる
Gozaru, gozaru, it's a sneak attack, gozaru.
魔法少女枠は寝ず高楊枝でござる
The magical girl slot stays wide awake and restless, gozaru.
ござる ござる 魔法の国から
Gozaru, gozaru, from the magical land,
忍びでまいおりた 謎の健康性
a mysterious healthy nature flying down as a shinobi.
魔法少女マジカルござる
Magical girl, magical gozaru.
こんばんは。風真いろはです。
Good evening. I am Kazama Iroha.
今日は3周年お祝い感謝！
Today is my 3rd anniversary celebration and thanks!
来てくれて本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much for coming!
最初に皆さんに少しだけお話をさせて下さい。
First, please let me talk to you all for a little bit.
お察しのとおりですが、
As you can probably guess,
今、声が出ません。
I currently have no voice.
原因は端的に言うと、
To put it simply, the cause is
ストレスからくる心因性
stress-induced psychogenic
失声症です。
aphonia.
お医者さんに診断いただきました。
I was diagnosed by a doctor.
端的な説明すぎて誤解を招きたくないので、はっきり言うと、
I don't want a brief explanation to cause misunderstandings, so to be clear,
クロエの卒業とは関係ないというか、
it has nothing to do with Chloe's graduation, or rather,
もちろん寂しいですが、
of course I'm sad about it,
正直今日の配信は前から不安でしたが、
to be honest, I've been anxious about today's stream beforehand,
でもそれだけが原因ではなく、
but that's not the only reason,
本当に誰かが悪いとかではないです。
it's truly not because anyone is to blame.
他のこともふくめ、心に負荷がかかりすぎた。
Including various other things, my mind was under too much stress.
それだけです。タイミングとかもある。
That's just it. There's also timing and stuff.
でも全部仕方ない。誰も悪くない。
But it can't be helped. Nobody is at fault.
しいて言えば
If I had to say...
己が弱い、これです。
It's that I'm weak—that's it.
明日、声が出るかもだし、ずっとでないかもだし、わかりませんが、
I don't know if my voice will come out tomorrow, or if it might not come out at all for a while...
今日は絶対、皆を1人にしたくなってわがまま言って配信しています
Today, I selfishly wanted to have you all to myself, so I'm streaming.
ご心配をおかけして本当にごめんなさい！
I'm so sorry for worrying you!
今日は楽しい気持ちで沢山皆さんと共有したく
Today, I wanted to share my happy feelings with all of you...
本当に来てくれてありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for coming.
今日ははおひめめあるので
Today we have the showcase, so...
今日は おひろめ あるので ゆっくり楽しんでいってね！
Today there's a reveal, so please sit back and enjoy!
元気になっていってね！
Hope you feel energized!
まず おひろめから！
First, the reveal!
いくよ！
Here we go!
では しばし待て。
Now, wait a moment.
おまたせ！^^
Thanks for waiting! ^^
ひんとは これね
The hint is right here.
いくつ？ てかてか？ はしれる？
How many? Shiny? Can you run?
くつしたは くるぶしかくした^^
Socks hiding the ankles ^^
はずだから くるぶしまでだし
They should be, reaching the ankles.
いつも思うの。
I always think...
いつも思うの、ママ！みじかいの、スキだよね
I always think, Mama! You like them short, don't you?
みじかい！走れる？？ふあん...
Short! Can you run in them?? Worried...
え！これもしや、もえそで...？ MOESODE...
Eh! Is this... moe sleeves...? MOESODE...
パーカーよく着るうれしいね！
I wear hoodies a lot, so I'm happy!
みてこれぽこべぇ！ゆらゆら
Look at this, Pokobee! Wobble wobble
またいる。セーラーだ！ファンアート多いの乗せた
It's here again. A sailor uniform! I put up one with lots of fan art.
うれしかった
I was so happy.
さいご、ズドっていくわ^^-b
Finally, zooming in with a *zudo*^^ -b
みっぁみ、どうよ！
Look at that, how is it!
全身みる？
Wanna see my full body?
天才っ。神っ。
Genius! God-tier!
しかも、うごくじゃん？ あついじゃん？
Plus, it moves? And it's awesome?
ぬげるヨ
You can take it off!
最近寒いから
Since it's been cold lately...
あったかいのあるよ
I've got a warm one!
いる
Here he is!
あと
And also...
はじめての…
My first...
散髪
Haircut!
イケメン
Handsome!
どれが好きかハイコメント
Let me know which one you like in the comments!
やったー！
Yay!
じつは今日、声が出なくて、
Actually, today my voice wouldn't come out,
ホロメン呼んだの、呼んでて？
so I called some Holomem to speak for me.
え、こちら雑談ってらっしゃるんでしょうか？
Eh, are you guys chatting?
やはりショートかー、カードが重い。可愛い、可愛い、マジでポルカ可愛い！
As expected, short hair! The cardigan is heavy. Cute, cute, Polka is seriously cute!
おさげ？おさげは
Twin tails? Twin tails...
ショートとちょっと分かれてて、どっちがいいかって話をしてたんだよ、ラプラスの魔で。
were separated from short hair, and we were talking about which one is better on Laplace-sama.
はいっ てるよー！ あの、え、えーっと、ラプラスど、どっちなんですか？
It's in there! Um, uh, which one is Laplace's?
いや、僕は完全におさげに騙されてますね。
No, I am completely fooled by the twin tails.
おさげでカーディガンです、おさげか？おさげでカーディガンです完全に。
Twin tails with a cardigan, twin tails? It's twin tails with a cardigan, for sure.
じゃ、おさげカーディガン入ります。
Then, twin tails cardigan, coming in.
これでおさげにしろって
Does this mean get twin tails?
のばせ、のばせ、のばせ、のばせ...
Grow it, grow it, grow it...
の、揺れんな、揺れんな。の、来たー！すげえ！さすが生足！きた！さすが生足！
Don't shake, don't shake. No, it's here! Amazing! As expected of bare legs! It's here! As expected of bare legs!
やば、カーディガンいいね。自分もいっ...自分もいっちゃってくださいよ。
Man, cardigans are nice. You should go for it too... You go for it too.
やっぱり、あのショートヘアで全部脱いだ、全部脱いだ...
As expected—taking it all off with short hair, taking it all off...
カーディガンと、あのパーカーをと...うちのいろはちゃんそういうのやってないんで、すいません！
The cardigan and that parka... Our Iroha-chan doesn't do that kind of thing, sorry!
いろはちゃん、髪の毛を三つ編みして、カーディガンをちょっと脱いでいただいて...寒いけどね、ごめんね。
Iroha-chan, braid your hair and take off the cardigan a bit... It's cold though, sorry.
ごめん、寒い、寒いんじゃない？寒いじゃん、いろはちゃん寒くないじゃん？
Sorry, cold—isn't it cold? It's cold, isn't Iroha-chan cold?
ばあ...あ、ばあ...うわ！これ！この生足！やば！
Ba... ah, ba... Wow! This! These bare legs! So crazy!
この制服のデザインが良いっすね。うちのホロライブに足りてないものかもしれない、いまこれ。
The uniform design is really good. Maybe this is what Hololive is lacking right now.
あ、そうだね。この光の感じがやばいです。光属性いなくなっていってる気がするもん、どんどん。
Ah, that's right. This lighting feel is crazy. It feels like light-attribute members are disappearing more and more.
そんなこと言わないで！みんなね、なんかゴスロリとかさ、着てるじゃん。
Don't say things like that! Everyone wears goth-loli and stuff, you know.
そこにこのいろはの、この制服ですよ。
And then we have Iroha's school uniform here.
あ、もう、ねえ、あのね、このホロライブのこのパサ、パッタリ感がもう逆に...
Ah, geez, you know, this kind of Hololive's abrupt contrast feels kind of...
珍しい！珍しくなくない？だってそのみんな結構さ、ゴテゴテ、キラキラって感じだけど。
Rare! Isn't it rare? Because everyone else is usually all flashy and sparkly.
あ、でもね、つける、いろはな、全部つける！
Ah, but you know, attaching—Iroha attaches everything!
ただの制服って...え、でもでも、いろはちゃん、
Just a uniform... Eh, but still, Iroha-chan,
やっぱこれを脱いだら、明日も普通にワンピースみたいなの...すぐ脱がせようとするの、やめてもらっていいですか？
if you take this off, normally tomorrow you'd have a one-piece-like dress... Could you please stop trying to make her strip immediately?
ないんだよね、普通にさ、これだってゆるゆる形式の服だし、ワンピースタイプね、ワンピースタイプ。
It's not like that, normally this is loose-style clothing, one-piece type, one-piece type.
うん、なんかワンピースタイプの服になるみたいなことはないの？これ、この上のこのTシャツのところ...
Hmm, isn't there something like it turning into a one-piece type outfit? This, on top of this T-shirt part...
水になってんだよ ほら下着が…
It's soaking wet... look, my underwear...
だってこんなに短い！短かったらもうだめでしょ！おへそ見えちゃうじゃん！
Because it's so short! If it's this short, that's no good! You can see my belly button!
いやだからその…ね、この上着はどうなってんのかな？
No, but you know... how is this jacket supposed to work?
気になる。
I'm curious.
ちょっと脱げたらなあ。
I wish I could take it off.
お母さんに怒れ…
My mom will get mad...
なんで？え、ちょっと見せてくれてるんですけど。
Why? Eh, but she's letting me show it a little.
ちょっと…ちょっと…ちょっと見せてもらえる。あ、あ、やばい、やばい、やばい。あ、これどうな…これどうなん？
Let me... let me show you. Ah, oh no, oh no. Ah, how is this... how is this?
だから、下側がワンピ…な、な、あの、あれ何なの？ ちょっとわかんない！
So, the bottom part is a dress... wh-wh-what is that? I don't get it!
もう揺るゆり揺るゆりすんなお前らだから。お前知識が足りんねん！
Stop swaying back and forth, you guys! You lack knowledge!
揺るゆり見ろよ。
Watch YuruYuri.
僕女の子のこと、わかんないよ！
I don't understand girls!
揺るゆりで分かるから女の子のこと。
You'll understand girls from YuruYuri.
そうなんの？
Is that so?
そうだよ。
That's right.
そうなんの？
Is that so?
なんか艶々だね。かわいい。
It's kind of glossy and shiny. Cute.
ローファーもね、よかったよすごく。
The loafers were really nice too.
なんかポルカさんあの、いろはさんの足について語ってましたよね。
Polka-san, you were talking about Iroha-san's feet earlier, right?
ああ、足ですか。あの、とてもシンプルながらすごくいい足をしていまして。あ、そうですね。
Ah, feet? Um, they're very simple yet have amazing legs. Ah, that's right.
なんか、ね、ちょっとスタンダードなおみあって感じで、はい。足。
Kind of, you know, like a standard pair of legs, yes. Legs.
わかります。
I understand.
このね、装飾とかない感じがいいんですよね。
The fact that there's no decoration is what's good about it.
それです！もうシンプル足っていう。
That's it! It's just simple legs.
そう、我が輩はそれが…我が、我が写っ…あ、それ取られたの？
Yeah, I... my, my reflected... Ah, did you take that?
取られたの？
Did you take it?
取られたのはいいと思う。
I think taking it is fine.
いや、本当に、おめでとう、3周年。いや、素敵ない衣装ですね。
Man, seriously, congratulations on the 3rd anniversary. What a wonderful outfit.
え、いろはつ…君は制服は？ ねぇよ、ねぇよ、ねぇよ。
Eh, Iroha... what about your uniform? None, none, none.
いやねぇよ！ってことはやはりこう夕リ人の匂わせなのだろうか。
No way! Could this be a hint about YuruYuri people?
あ、やめてください！なんでカーディガンを選んだんだね？
Ah, please stop! Why did you choose a cardigan?
え、やん！なんでカーディガンにしたの？
Eh, why did you make it a cardigan?
なんかカーディガンもあるよね、いろはちゃん。なんでやろ…なんで小ゆりさんと並んだらこんな匂わせみたいな…すしすしすし。
Cardigans exist too, right, Iroha-chan? I wonder why... why does standing next to Koyuri-san feel like such a hint... sushi sushi sushi.
なんかこう、小ゆりさんと並んだらすっごくバランスが良さそうだよね。そうそうそうそう。あの、なんか「あ、もう強制的に制服衣装を作らなければいけないような」この焦りを感じるのですが。
Standing next to Koyuri-san makes the balance look really good. That's right. Like, "Ah, I feel this rush like I'm forced to make a uniform outfit."
いやいやいや、ルイルイも着なきゃいけないから。そうすればルイルイも。
No no no, Ruirui has to wear it too. Then Ruirui too.
るいるいるい…ルイルイさんの制服衣装がさ、あれなんか、あれ先生みたい。あ、それっぽいそれっぽい、先生っぽいから、じゃあ、先生っぽいから。
Ruirui... Ruirui's uniform outfit looks like a teacher. Ah, that's it, that's it, looks like a teacher, so yeah, looks like a teacher.
え、だからごめんね。
Eh, so sorry.
あ、いろはしプレゼント送ったんですけど、これつけられます？ いろはし、あの、いろはさん煽るのやめてもらってよろしいか？
Ah, Iroha-shi, I sent a present, can you wear this? Iroha-shi, um, could you stop provoking Iroha-san?
ごめんね。あの、マジで煽るのをやめてもらっていいか。
Sorry. Um, seriously, can you stop provoking me.
ばらばら。
Lol lol.
コメントやめてね。ごめんねばらばら。
Stop commenting. Sorry, lol lol.
あ、いろはちゃん、ちょっとそうだよプレゼント見たひっすね。
Ah, Iroha-chan, let's see the present.
ちょっと、ねえこれいけます？
Wait, hey, can you wear this?
こ、ちょっと、これいけます？ かけていただきたい。
W-wait, can you wear this? I want you to put it on.
どうすか？
How is it?
なんか、なんかします。
It's doing something.
準備し、していいから全然。
You can prepare, it's fine.
俺ら喋ってるからさ。
We're talking.
あ、そうそうそう！こっち喋る全然。
Ah, yeah yeah yeah! We'll talk over here.
あ、汚い、それだめじゃん！おめでとうこそ喋る。汚いことやめてくださいよ！
Ah, gross, that's no good! Congratulations on talking. Please stop saying gross things!
いや、3周年っすよ、いろはさんの。
Man, it's the 3rd anniversary, Iroha-san's.
3周年！
3rd anniversary!
先輩！3周年！
Senpai! 3rd anniversary!
いや、待った待った！
No, wait wait!
あの、色々お披露目って言ってさ、こんなに大々的にお洋服来ると、きったー！お、お、お、お、お、お、お、でかすぎんだろ！お、お、え、でか！ちょっ、お前、待て待て待て！
Um, saying it's a various reveal, when you wear clothes so grandly... it's here! O- too big! O- eh, huge! Wait, hey, wait wait wait!
え、いや、いいっすよ。やっぱりマジカルゴサルノの時のミュージックビデオで出てきたメガネ、これ似合いますね。
Eh, well, it's fine. After all, the glasses that appeared in the Magical Gosaruno music video suit you.
やはりこの形、あー、ちょっと待て！そしたら、え、ルイルイもしもしお下げにしないといけないんじゃないではないか？
Indeed this shape, ah, wait a minute! Then, eh, shouldn't Ruirui also put her hair in pigtails?
あ、確かに！お下げ、お下げがいいじゃないですか。やはりこれはマジカルゴサルの再現をしたほうがよろしいかと思う。
Ah, true! Pigtails, pigtails are good. I think it's better to recreate Magical Gosaru.
つまりじゃあお下げにしたほうがいいということですね。そうそう普通に考えてお下げ。
In other words, it means we should put it in pigtails. Yeah, normally thinking, pigtails.
お下げにして持って、持って、そんなに無理してお下げにしないことよ。
Put it in pigtails and hold it, hold it, you don't have to force pigtails.
普通に考えてお下げ。
Normally thinking, pigtails.
お下げ仕様で。
In pigtail style.
はいよ。あお、あーげ。あー、きたー！
Alright. A-o-, a-ge. Ah, it's here!
いやー、これ、や、ポルカさんいいメガネ買ってきたね。
Man, this, well, Polka-san bought some nice glasses.
我が一生に一ぺんの悔いなし！それでは！
There are no regrets in my life! Then!
あいつ消えた！
That guy disappeared!
ポルカあーー！
Polkaaaaa!
消えました。
She disappeared.
じゃあいろはちゃん。
Well then, Iroha-chan.
頑張ったの。ちゅちゅちゅちゅちゅちゅちゅちゅ…
You did your best. Chu chu chu chu chu...
うれしいね！
I'm so happy!
あ、もしもし、いろは先輩！入っちゃって大丈夫でしょうか？
Ah, hello, Iroha-senpai! Is it okay to come in?
こんにちは、こがねいここと申します！いろは先輩3周年おめでとうございます！
Hello, my name is Koganei Iko! Congratulations on your 3rd anniversary, Iroha-senpai!
あ、えっと、あ、す、すみません、緊張してるんですけど、あの
Ah, um, ah, s-sorry, I'm feeling nervous, but um
こんにちは、こっちもです！
Hello, me too!
こんにちは、えっと、自己紹介とホロライブデバイスプログラムのこがねいここと申します。
Hello, um, I am Koganei Iko of the self-introduction and Hololive Dev_is program.
いろは先輩3周年おめでとうございます！
Congratulations on your 3rd anniversary, Iroha-senpai!
いや、直接お祝いできてめちゃめちゃ嬉しいです。
Man, I'm so, so happy to congratulate you in person.
いやいやいやいやいやいや
No, no, no, no, no, no!
嬉しいでござる！嬉しいでござる！
I'm so happy! I'm so happy!
めっちゃ緊張する、あー
I'm so nervous, ah—
ちょっとですね、やばかったですね、
Well, you know, it was pretty crazy,
いろは先輩のこの清掃、叶いません
I can't compete with Iroha-senpai's purity like this.
叶いません、ちょっと。
I can't compete, sort of.
超清掃です。あー、なんか、すいません！
It's super pure. Ah, wait, sorry!
後ろに、後ろの、後ろに住み着いてる！
She's living right behind me!
どうしよう！どうしよう！
What should I do? What should I do?
後ろに、あ、何で動かないの？
Behind me—ah, why won't she move?
ちょっと待って、すいません、なんか、固まってる、なんで？
Wait a second, sorry, she's kind of frozen. Why?
ごめんなさい！
I'm sorry!
いろは先輩、すいません！
Iroha-senpai, I'm sorry!
ちょっと、大丈夫ですか？静止画でも。
Um, are you okay? Even as a still image.
すいません、こっちだと動いてるんですけど
Sorry, she's moving on my end, though.
いや、ちょっとね、やっぱり、いろは先輩みたいに、
Well, you know, just like Iroha-senpai,
清掃でかっこいい金髪美少女になれるように、ちょっと、二コも頑張りたいと思います
I want to work hard to become a pure, cool blonde bishoujo too, Nico.
えっ！かっこいい…！えっ…！
Eh! Cool...! Eh...!
いろは先輩にはかないませんよ！かっこよさも…！
I can't hold a candle to Iroha-senpai! Her coolness too...!
いや、もちろんあの、二コはですね、いろは先輩のさやですので
Well, of course, Nico is Iroha-senpai's saya, so...
はい、ちょっとこちらを今回お届けさせていただきたいと思います
Yes, I'd like to present this to you this time.
えっと、さや！
Um, Saya!
あ、ほい。あ、ほい。どん！
Ah, hoi. Ah, hoi. Don!
こちら、いろは先輩のさやけんでございます！
Here is Iroha-senpai's Sayaken!
きた！
It's here!
こちらぜひいつでも呼んでいただけたらさやになりますので！
Please feel free to call me anytime and I'll become Saya!
やばい！出されると恥ずかしい！
Oh no! It's so embarrassing when it's put out!
ぜひぜひあの、今後ともよろしくお願いします、いろは先輩！
Please treat me well in the future too, Iroha-senpai!
あの、最後に、お願いがあるんですけど…！
Um, I have one last request...!
えっ、ぜひぜひお願いしまっす！
Eh, please, absolutely!
一緒に、ござる合戦しましょう！
Let's do a 'gozaru' battle together!
あの、最後に、お願いがあるんですけど、いろは先輩。
Um, I have a request at the end, Iroha-senpai.
にこたんって、あの、文字でいいので呼んでいただけないかなと思って。こがねいさんもいいんですけど
I was wondering if you could call me 'Nikotan' in text. Koganei-san is fine too, but...
こがねいさんもいいんですけど、にこたんって呼んでいただけたらもう発狂して出ていきます！にこたん…！
Koganei-san is good too, but if you call me Nikotan, I'll go crazy and come out! Nikotan...!
ああっ！いろは先輩…！ああっ！大好きです！ありがとうございました！
Ahhh! Iroha-senpai...! Ahhh! I love you! Thank you very much!
みなさま、失礼いたしました。
Everyone, excuse me.
にこたん、ありがとう！！
Nikotan, thank you!!
おお、よーよーよーよーよーよーよー
Oh, yo-yo-yo-yo-yo-yo-yo!
なんか、俺とさや、やっぱりさ、
Like, me and Saya, as expected,
動かないね？
aren't moving, right?
こうやってさ、動いてはいるけどさ、ござるはさ、固まってんだよね？
Like this, we're moving, but Gozaru is frozen, right?
これは、こっちの問題なのかな？どうなんだろね、ござるさん。
Is this a problem on our end? I wonder, Gozaru-san.
おまち！おまち！
Wait! Wait!
ござる多分ね、最新じゃあないでござる！
Gozaru is probably not up to date!
そう、それじゃあなかろうか。あ
That... must be it. Ah.
そう、だね。うっ…いろは、過去に取り残されてんだな、ござるは
That's right. Urgh... Iroha has been left behind in the past, Gozaru has.
で、ござるが寝てしまってさ、画面にはふと
And, Gozaru fell asleep, and suddenly on screen...
もはやわかんないさやがあるだけだ。このさや、大丈夫か？
There's just a Saya that we don't even know anymore. Is this Saya okay?
おしりか？おしり？なのかな？そのさや、大丈夫か？
An ass? An ass? Is that it? Is that Saya okay?
ござる、の、ござるの画面は大丈夫か？おしり…さや…？あれにこざるがいなくなっ…大丈夫か？
Gozaru, is Gozaru's screen okay? Ass... Saya...? Huh, Nikozaru is gone... Is she okay?
ちがうひときた！
A different person came!
ちがうひときたｗｗｗ
A different person came lol
みんなにみせれんｗｗｗ
Can't show this to everyone lol
あ！
Ah!
じゅつこら始めてる、あ、ある意味、ある意味そうだね
Starting... Ah, in a way, I guess that's true.
じゅつこさま同時配信してる、あ、来た来た来た！
Jutsu-sama is streaming simultaneously. Ah, they're here!
イェーイ！ガタッ！
Yay! *clatter*
あのさ、よかったらふぶの、上半身アップ目に映してショートになってくれないかい？
Say, if you don't mind, could you show my upper body close-up and become short?
そう、上半身アップめで、ショートになってほしいんだ。ちょっと気づいてしまったことがあるんだよね。
Yeah, I want you to do an upper body close-up and become short. I just realized something.
最初に上半身アップに、でショートになってくれないかと。
First doing an upper body close-up, and won't you become short?
これさ、あなた僕たち初対面感じない？
Don't you feel like this is our first time meeting?
僕たちすごく初対面感じないかい？僕はねんねんそう思ってるよ。
Don't you feel like we've just met? I've been thinking that all along.
あのさ、声が出るようになったらコラボしないか？ホロライブのお姉ちゃんたちをまとう。
Say, once you can use your voice, won't you collab with me? Embodying Hololive's big sisters.
あの、なかなかホロライブにね、ショートがいないから、いろはくん、いろはくんがショートになって...
Well, since there aren't many shorts in Hololive, Iroha-kun, won't you become a short...
僕初対面を...感じるから、
Because I feel like we've just met...
この僕とじゃあ一緒に声が出たらショート配信をしよう。ぼくおねーさんすき！
When you can use your voice, let's do a short stream together with me. I love big sisters!
わかる、僕もおねーさん好きでホロライブのおねーさんいい人ばっかだからね。
I know right? I love big sisters too, and Hololive's big sisters are all such great people.
じゃあいろはくん、じゃあ声出せるようになったらじゃあ僕と一緒にショートにして、ホロライブのおねーさんたちをいっぱい、いっぱい呼びまくろう。
So Iroha-kun, once you can use your voice, let's become shorts together and call out Hololive's big sisters as much as we can!
さっきのは、やる！やるます！やったー！
That just now—I'll do it! I will do it! Yay!
さっきのは、3周年おめでとう、だねー！
That just now was "Happy 3rd Anniversary," right!
つれぇ...
So painful...
ありがとうございます、スブ先輩！
Thank you very much, Subu-senpai!
祝！3周年 いろはがめおと！！
Congrats! 3rd Anniversary Iroha & Meoto!!
キャップ着用！＆衣装変え 無言ですまん！！！
Wearing a cap! & Outfit change. Sorry for being silent!!!
ドーナツ美味い！！！また遊ぼう！！！ みお先輩
Donuts are delicious!!! Let's play again!!! - Mio-senpai
ありがとうございますTT
Thank you very much TT
W
Lol
笑いすぎたw
Laughed too much lol
他にもたくさん
Lots of others too
写真もらいました。
We got photos taken!
みなさん 本当に ありがとうございます！
Everyone, thank you so much!
じゃあ ちょっと 告知してもいいかな？
Now then, shall I make some announcements?
というわけで 告知です！
And so, it's announcement time!
まずは これ！
First off, is this!
活動3周年記念グッズが いよいよ発売されます！
Her 3rd anniversary merch is finally here!
ラインナップみてて！
Let's take a look at the lineup!
1つめ、ブランケット。暖かい！
Number one, a fluffy blanket.
リバーシブルです！
It's reversible, too!
その2！
Number two!
ぽこべぇ アイマスク。
Check out this Pokobee eye mask!
フェス、イベントで使える…
It's super cute for events!
ぽこべぇ アイマスク
[Ponpoko Eye Mask]
ころりんぽこべぇぬいぐるみ
[Kororin Ponpoko Plushie]
ランダムアクリルキーホルダー
[Random Acrylic Keyholder]
活動3周年記念フルセット
[3rd Anniversary Full Set]
フルセット購入特典
[Full Set Purchase Bonus]
魂けずってます。
I'm pouring my soul into this.
よろしくお願いします
Thank you for your support.
そして
And...
もう一つ
one more
告知があります！！
announcement to make!!
新しいオリ曲です！
It's a brand new original song!
この曲の説明は
I'll explain this song
この後のミニライブでしてます
in the mini-live right after this!
よかったらさいごまでみてってください！
Please watch until the end if you'd like!
MVは配信終了後に
The MV should direct you
ダイレクトでとばされるはず
right after the stream ends!
なんと・・・
And...
恋愛ソングですすご！w
it's a love song! Amazing! lol
リリースは
The release is
12/1 24じです！
on December 1st at 24:00!
げんていうりきれたま・・・？
The limited edition sold out...?!
たくさん用意したんだがいつも瞬殺
I prepared a lot, but they always sell out instantly.
ほんとうにすまん いつもありがとうございます
I'm really sorry... Thank you as always.
では今日の最後
Now, for today's final part,
3Dライブ
a 3D live!
こちらは誕生日のときに事前収録しました。
This was pre-recorded around my birthday.
今回のためにいろいろ使えるリソース調整してつくりました！
I adjusted various resources to make this happen for this occasion!
こちらは誕生日のときに
This was pre-recorded
事前収録しました。
around my birthday.
今回のために
I made this specially
いろいろ誕生日でつかえるリソース調整してつくりました！
by adjusting various birthday resources!
今日初めてのかざまの声だね
This is the first time hearing Kazama's voice today, right?
すこしでも元気になっていってくれたうれしいです！
I'd be happy if you feel even a little more energized!
それではさっそく
Now then, let's go
ミニライブGo!
straight to the mini-live, Go!
そのあとはMV公開！
After that is the MV premiere!
さいごまで楽しんでいってね！！
Please enjoy it to the very end!!
まちがえた ^ ^
I made a mistake ^^
こんどこそ！
This time for sure!
風がそっと吹いたら
When the wind softly blows,
始まる合図でござる！
It's the signal to begin, deござる!
Ah このハードモードな日々
Ah, these hard-mode days,
Days 歩き出すことためらうけど
Days when I hesitate to step forward,
BGM決めてさあ、人生エンジョイ勢でのんびりいこう
Set your BGM, let's enjoy life and take it easy!
先の見えない乱世
In this turbulent age with no clear future,
自分の道通りゃんせ
Walk your own path proudly!
オーケー 生きてりゃきっとなんとかなるさ
Okay, as long as you're alive, things will work out!
だいじょうぶだいじょうぶ！
It's gonna be alright, alright!
後ろ？前？方向なんてわからない
Back? Front? I don't even know the direction,
こんな迷宮入りな毎日も
Even in such a labyrinthine daily life,
一歩歩き出せたら
If I can take just one step forward,
それが前になるのさ
That will become the front!
万事快調気味な朝でも
Even on a morning when everything feels great,
頭滞気味な夜でも
Or a sluggish night with a foggy head,
風がいつも吹いている心配しないで
The wind is always blowing, so don't worry,
一緒にファイトでござる！
Let's fight together, deござる!
Ah まだ履き慣れてない
Ah, shoes I'm not yet used to wearing,
シューズ 転びそうになってばかり
Shoes that keep making me stumble,
七転び八起き 何回でもゲームオーバー コンティニューしよう
Fall down seven times, get up eight, game over—let's continue!
地獄の沙汰も自分次第
Hell's affairs depend on yourself,
たまにミスって非常事態
Sometimes you make a mistake and it's an emergency,
ジーザス 生きてりゃそういうときだってあるさ
Jesus, there are times like that when you're alive!
だいじょうぶだいじょうぶ！
It's gonna be alright, alright!
1.2.3が聞こえない
1, 2, 3 can't be heard,
よもや突発的な運命も
Even unexpected sudden destinies,
グッドタイミングな予感
Feel like good timing!
思い立ったが吉日さ
The best day to start is right when you think of it,
いつも現実主義なあの人も
Even that person who is always a realist,
かたや妄想癖な誰かも
Or someone who is prone to delusions,
夢の中で会えたら遊び明かしましょう
If we can meet in a dream, let's play all night!
それじゃあねおやすみ
Well then, goodnight!
色は匂へと散りぬるを
Though colors drift away and scatter,
終わりのないはじまりを
An endless beginning,
歌いながら風のままにゆけ！
Singing along, go with the wind!
ゆけ！
Go!
後ろ前 方向なんてわからない
I don't know front from back, or which way is which.
こんな迷宮入りな毎日も
Even in days like this maze of a daily life,
一歩 歩き出せたら
if I can take a step forward,
それが前に成るのさ
that will become the front.
万事快調 気分な朝でも
Whether it's a perfectly smooth morning,
頭痛気味な夜でも
or a night with a slight headache,
風がいつも吹いてる 心配しないで
the wind is always blowing, so don't worry.
自分のペースで 一緒にファイトで
At your own pace, fighting together—
ござる！ござる！
gozaru! gozaru!
はい、というわけで、皆さまこんばんはでござる！
Hi, everyone, good evening for gozaru!
風真いろは3周年記念ミニライブにお越しいただきまして、ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much for coming to Kazama Iroha's 3rd Anniversary Mini-Live!
え？
Eh?
風真の今年は、周年3Dライブなかったんじゃないの？って思っているそこのあなた。
For those of you thinking, "Wasn't there supposed to be an anniversary 3D live this year?"—
実はですね、こちらは今年の誕生日の準備のリソースをお願いして使わせていただいて、特別に収録して澱ます。
actually, this was specially recorded using resources prepared for my birthday this year.
なので、今なんとう収録しているのは風真の誕生日ということで！
So, what we are recording right now is actually Kazama's birthday!
だいぶ前になるんですけども。
Even though it's quite a while ago.
未来の大祭さん、そして未来の風真いろは、見ってる～？
Future Taisen-san, and future Kazama Iroha, are you watching?
という種明かしでございました！はい、もしやしないかな、嬉しいって言ってくれてる大祭さんも
That was the big reveal! I'm sure Taisen-san, who's saying "No way, I'm so happy,"
きっとコメント欄にいるんじゃないかなって思うと、
is probably right there in the comment section,
今ちょっと想像して嬉しい気持ちになっています。今日は、周年記念配信見て下さり、本当にありがとうございます！
so imagining that makes me feel so happy. Thank you so much for watching the anniversary stream today!
きっとね、今から比べたら11月の30日でしょう？今よりも歌絶対上手くなってるし、今よりも絶対に踊り上手くなっているはずなんですけれども、今の全力一杯をね、今回このミニライブに詰めさせていただいております！
Compared to November 30th, I'm sure I'm better at singing and dancing now, but I've poured all my energy into this mini-live!
ああ、この後見せるのがドキドキするぜ！そして、今回ですね、どうしてミニライブをやったかっていうのがもう一つ理由がありまして、
Ah, my heart is pounding showing this afterwards! And another reason why we did this mini-live is...
なんとですね、皆さまのこの度風真いろは新しいオリジナル曲を発表させていただくこととなりました！
that I will be announcing a brand new original song for Kazama Iroha!
わあ！そうなんです、このタイミングで今日新オリジナル曲を公開させていただきます！
Yay! That's right, at this timing, I am releasing a brand new original song today!
はい、今回はですね、いろんな今までオリジナル曲があったと思うんですけど、「いろはステップ」は可愛い感じ、あと「万次郎ござる」は結構ね、なんかポップなキャッチーな感じ、
There have been various original songs so far: "Iroha Step!" has a cute vibe, "Manjiro Gozaru" has a catchy pop vibe,
「Dreamy Dessert」もそんな可愛い感じ、魔法少女の感じですね。そして、「風神和義」でようなかっこいい感じでした。
"Dreamy Dessert" is also cute, magical girl style. And "Fūjin Kazayoshi" had a cool vibe.
結構いろんなオリジナル曲を作ってきたんですけども、今回の曲は、なんと！風真いろはの性格的なところを
I've made quite a variety of original songs, but this time's song is—surprise!—a song that fully brings out Kazama Iroha's personality.
全面に出した曲となっております。はい、皆さんと3年の風真いろはにお付き合いいただきましたら、風真いろはがとてもちょっと恥ずかしいのが苦手とかね、
Yes, after spending 3 years with Kazama Iroha, many of you know that Kazama Iroha hates being embarrassed,
そういった内面があるのはもちろん大祭さんはもうご存知の方も多いと思うんですけれども、その内面と今回は恋愛感をマッチさせた恋愛ソングを作らせていただきました！
and I had a love song created that matches those inner feelings!
恥ずかしくって発作が起きそうです。けどね、自分のやっぱ内面とかそういうのを表現したい、
It's so embarrassing I feel like I'll have a spasm. But you know, I wanted to express my inner self,
今年は1年オリジナル曲をいっぱい作りたいということで活動してまいりました。そのため今回もですね、周年で1個公開させていただき、
and that's why I've been active wanting to make lots of original songs this year, and release one for the anniversary.
新たな一面を出せればと思っております。はい、ちょっと今発表する前にドキドキしてしょうがないので、この後歌うんですけれども、そう、このミニライブで初披露になるんですが、その前に1回お水飲んできますね。
Yes, my heart is pounding so much before announcing it, and although I'll sing after this—my first performance in this mini-live—let me go drink some water first.
ちょっとお水飲ませていただきます。
Let me have some water.
お水、お水、このお水の踊りね、お水の踊り。はい、というわけで、改めまして風真いろはのちょっと内面的ない性格を含んだ新オリジナル曲、そして初めての恋愛ソングとなります。
Water, water, this water dance... Yes, so once again, this is Kazama Iroha's brand new original song incorporating her inner personality, and her first love song.
ここでミニライブで初披露させていただきます。それでは皆様聞いてください。ポリスピカデリーさん作詞作曲、風真いろは新オリジナル曲「ハードモード」！
I will perform it for the first time here in the mini-live. Everyone, please listen to it. Written and composed by Police Piccadilly, Kazama Iroha's brand new original song, "Hard Mode"!
ダメだ 果てしない
"No good, it's endless."
想定の半端くらい？
"About half of what was expected?"
もうそれ以上は 言えない無駄っぽい
"Any more than that seems useless to say."
まだ届いてない？
"Still hasn't reached it?"
不協和音 調
"Dissonant tone..."
伝えるまでがミッション 賽は投げられた
Until I convey it, it's a mission—the die is cast.
皮肉なものの内心ボロボロ
Ironic, yet inside I'm beat to pieces.
息してるだけで褒めてくれよな
Just for breathing, praise me, won't you?
モヤモヤよこの指とまれ
Fuzzy feelings, rest upon this finger.
絶対なんて無いね絶対
There's no such thing as "absolute"—absolutely!
悪魔的予行演習リピート
A demonic dress rehearsal on repeat.
大怪我しないためにもね
So I don't get seriously hurt, you see.
重い想いぶん積もってく
Heavy feelings pile up higher and higher.
今はこれが現実
Right now, this is reality.
ダメだ果てしない
No good, it's endless.
想定の半分くらい？
About half of what I expected?
もうそれ以上は言えない無理っぽい
I can't say anything more than that, seems impossible.
まだ届いてない？ズキュン合図を頂戴
Still not reaching you? Give me a heart-piercing signal!
伝えるまでがミッション 賽は投げられた
Until I convey it, it's a mission—the die is cast.
伝えるまでがミッション どうにか届いて
Until I convey it, it's a mission—somehow reach them!
ここにもほら潜んでるトラップ 詳細情報は非公開 ご理解ください
Look, traps are lurking here too. Details are private, please understand.
君の横顔見つめるだけの専門家かな？
Am I just an expert who only stares at your profile?
お茶を濁してください
Soothe things over, won't you?
新しい季節が来ても
Even if a new season arrives,
1ミリも進んでないぜ
I haven't advanced a single millimeter.
重い想いぶん沈んでく
Heavy feelings sink down deeper and deeper.
今はそれも事実
Right now, even that is a fact.
ダメだ果てしない
No good, it's endless.
恐いけど知りたい ねぇそれ以上は望んでないよ
It's scary, but I want to know. Hey, I don't wish for anything more than that.
鼓動がやばくない？ ごめん合図を頂戴
Isn't my heartbeat crazy? Sorry, give me a signal!
伝えるまでがミッション ハードモード 叶えて
Until I convey it, it's a mission—Hard Mode, make it come true.
ダメだ果てしない
No good, it's endless.
想定の半分くらい？
About half of what I expected?
もうそれ以上は言えない無理っぽい
I can't say anything more than that, seems impossible.
まだ届いてない？ズキュン合図を頂戴
Still not reaching you? Give me a heart-piercing signal!
伝えるまでがミッション 賽は投げられた
Until I convey it, it's a mission—the die is cast.
伝えるまでがミッション どうにか届いて
Until I convey it, it's a mission—somehow reach them!
待ってて
Wait for me.
伝えるまでがミッション 賽は投げられた
Until I convey it, it's a mission—the die is cast.
Let's Go！ときめいた青空で もっと風に乗り きらめくの
Let's Go! In a heart-fluttering blue sky, riding the wind to sparkle even more.
Dreaming 今より可愛くなりたい
Dreaming, I want to be cuter than I am now.
Cuteな想い ほら何度でも バッキュンだ！
Cute feelings—look, a heart-shot anytime!
瞳にうつる ほうき星
A shooting star reflected in my eyes.
夜空の中 飛び込んだ Shiny Girl
A Shiny Girl who plunged right into the night sky.
手が届きそうなほど 近づく三日月 合図して
Close enough to touch—getting close to the crescent moon, give a signal.
街の明かりを数えたら
When I count the city lights,
眠りにつく枕元 Secret Girl
A Secret Girl at my bedside falling asleep.
まだ見つからない夢 探しに行こう
Let's go search for a dream we haven't found yet.
雨の日でも 晴れの日でも 真っ直ぐに咲いてる花のように
Like a flower blooming straight and tall, whether on rainy days or sunny days.
いつだって きっと どこだって そっと 輝く魔法
A shining magic, always and surely, gently anywhere.
Let's Go！ときめいた青空で もっと風に乗り きらめくの
Let's Go! In a heart-fluttering blue sky, riding the wind to sparkle even more.
Dreaming 今より可愛くなりたい
Dreaming, I want to be cuter than I am now.
Cuteな想い ほら何度でも バッキュンだ！
Cute feelings—look, a heart-shot anytime!
華やかなドレス身に纏い 誰かを待つ 憧れの Princess Girl
Clad in a gorgeous dress, an admired Princess Girl waiting for someone.
あー なりたい理想と比べてばっか
Ah, always comparing myself to the ideal I want to be.
道に迷って 1人悩んで 挫けそうになっても 大丈夫！
Even if I get lost, worry alone, and feel like giving up—it's okay!
君と出会って 笑顔になって 輝く魔法
Meeting you made me smile, a shining magic.
Let's Go！ありふれた日常も もっと風吹いて 動き出す
Let's Go! Even an ordinary daily life starts moving as the wind blows more.
Jumping 飛び立つ希望を探して
Jumping, searching for hope to take flight.
弾ける想い ほら何度でも バッキュンだ！
Bursting feelings—look, a heart-shot anytime!
本当に本当にありがとう
Thank you so, so much.
助けられるだけじゃない 私も守りたい
It's not just about being helped, I want to protect you too.
そうずっと想い描いた 日々を繋いで
Connecting the days I always dreamed of,
重なるいろは やっと気づいた本当の願い
overlapping Iroha, I finally realized my true wish.
なんてちょっぴり大袈裟だけど
That might be a bit of an exaggeration, but
どうかこの時間がいつまでも続きますように
I hope this time will last forever.
君と今 Let's Go! ときめいた青空で
With you right now, Let's Go! In the sparkling blue sky,
もっと風に乗りきらめくの
riding the wind even more and sparkling,
Dreaming 今より可愛くなりたい
Dreaming, I want to be cuter than now,
Cuteな想い ほら何度でもバッキュンだ！
and with cute feelings, shoot you with love anytime!
今日も本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much for today too!
これからもよろしくおねがいします！
I look forward to your continued support!